<codeBook
    xsi:schemaLocation="ddi:codebook:2_5 http://www.ddialliance.org/Specification/DDI-Codebook/2.5/XMLSchema/codebook.xsd" xmlns="ddi:codebook:2_5" version="2.5" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" codeBookAgency="us.icpsr" ID="ICPSR-37901">
    <docDscr>
        <citation>
            <titlStmt>
                <titl>Metadata record for Survey of Consumer Attitudes and Behavior, January 2017</titl>
                <IDNo agency="ICPSR">37901</IDNo>
            </titlStmt>
            <prodStmt>
                <producer abbr="ICPSR">Inter-university Consortium for Political and Social Research</producer>
                <copyright>ICPSR metadata records are licensed under a Creative Commons Attribution-Noncommercial 3.0 United States License <ExtLink URI="http://creativecommons.org/licenses/by-nc/3.0/us/"/></copyright>
            </prodStmt>
        </citation>
    </docDscr>
    <stdyDscr>
        <citation>
            <titlStmt>
                <titl>Survey of Consumer Attitudes and Behavior, January 2017</titl>
                <altTitl>Surveys of Consumers</altTitl>
                <IDNo agency="ICPSR">37901</IDNo>
                <IDNo agency="DataCite">https://doi.org/10.3886/ICPSR37901.v1</IDNo>
            </titlStmt>
            <rspStmt>
                <AuthEnty>University of Michigan. Survey Research Center. Economic Behavior Program</AuthEnty>
            </rspStmt>
            <distStmt>
                <distrbtr abbr="ICPSR" affiliation="Institute for Social Research, University of Michigan">Inter-university Consortium for Political and Social Research</distrbtr>
                <distDate date="2023-03-30">March 30, 2023</distDate>
            </distStmt>
            <verStmt>
                <version date="2023-03-30">V1</version>
                <notes>&lt;p&gt;2023-03-30 ICPSR data undergo a confidentiality review and are altered when necessary to limit the risk of disclosure. ICPSR also routinely creates ready-to-go data files along with setups in the major statistical software formats as well as standard codebooks to accompany the data. In addition to these procedures, ICPSR performed the following processing steps for this data collection:&lt;/p&gt;&lt;ul&gt;&lt;li&gt;Created variable labels and/or value labels.&lt;/li&gt;&lt;li&gt;Created online analysis version with question text.&lt;/li&gt;&lt;li&gt;Checked for undocumented or out-of-range codes.&lt;/li&gt;&lt;/ul&gt;</notes>
            </verStmt>
            <biblCit>University of Michigan. Survey Research Center. Economic Behavior Program. Survey of Consumer Attitudes and Behavior, January 2017.  [distributor], 2023-03-30. https://doi.org/10.3886/ICPSR37901.v1</biblCit>
            <holdings URI="https://doi.org/10.3886/ICPSR37901.v1"></holdings>
            <serStmt>
                <serName>Survey of Consumer Attitudes and Behavior Series</serName>
            </serStmt>
        </citation>
        <stdyInfo>
            <subject>
                <keyword vocab="ICPSR thesaurus">consumer attitudes</keyword>
                <keyword vocab="ICPSR thesaurus">consumer expectations</keyword>
                <keyword vocab="ICPSR thesaurus">consumer expenditures</keyword>
                <keyword vocab="ICPSR thesaurus">economic policy</keyword>
                <keyword vocab="ICPSR thesaurus">financial planning</keyword>
                <keyword vocab="ICPSR thesaurus">government</keyword>
                <keyword vocab="ICPSR thesaurus">home ownership</keyword>
                <keyword vocab="ICPSR thesaurus">household expenditures</keyword>
                <keyword vocab="ICPSR thesaurus">household income</keyword>
                <keyword vocab="ICPSR thesaurus">interest rates</keyword>
                <keyword vocab="ICPSR thesaurus">investments</keyword>
                <keyword vocab="ICPSR thesaurus">national economy</keyword>
                <keyword vocab="ICPSR thesaurus">retirement</keyword>
                <keyword vocab="ICPSR thesaurus">stock markets</keyword>
                <keyword vocab="ICPSR thesaurus">unemployment</keyword>
            </subject>
            <abstract contentType="abstract">&lt;p&gt;The Survey of Consumer Attitudes and Behavior series (also known as the Surveys of Consumers) was undertaken to measure changes in consumer attitudes and expectations, to understand why such changes occur, and to evaluate how they relate to consumer decisions to save, borrow, or make discretionary purchases. The data regularly include the Index of Consumer Sentiment, the Index of Current Economic Conditions, and the Index of Consumer Expectations. Since the 1940s, these surveys have been produced quarterly through 1977 and monthly thereafter.&lt;/p&gt; &lt;p&gt;The surveys conducted in 2017 focused on topics such as evaluations and expectations about personal finances, employment, price changes, and the national business situation. Opinions were collected regarding respondents' appraisals of present market conditions for purchasing houses, automobiles, computers, and other durables. Also explored in this survey, were respondents' types of savings and financial investments, loan use, family income, and retirement planning.&lt;/p&gt; &lt;p&gt;Other topics in this series typically include ownership, lease, and use of automobiles, respondents' use of personal computers at home and in the office, and respondents' familiarity with and use of the internet. Demographic information includes ethnic origin, sex, age, marital status, and education.&lt;/p&gt;</abstract>
            <abstract contentType="purpose">STUDY PURPOSE: The purpose of this survey series is to forecast changes in aggregate consumer behavior.</abstract>
            <abstract contentType="mixed">STUDY DESIGN: This survey is a rotating panel design. For each monthly sample, an independent cross-section sample of households is drawn. The respondents chosen in this drawing are then reinterviewed six months later. The result is a rotating panel design, and the total sample for any one survey is normally made up of 60 percent new respondents with 40 percent being interviewed for the second time.</abstract>
            <sumDscr>
                <timePrd event="start" date="2017-01">2017-01</timePrd>
                <collDate event="start" date="2016-12-27">2016-12-27</collDate>
                <collDate event="end" date="2017-01-23">2017-01-23</collDate>
                <geogCover>United States</geogCover>
                <geogUnit>FIPS code</geogUnit>
                <anlyUnit>Household</anlyUnit>
                <anlyUnit>Individual</anlyUnit>
                <universe>Persons aged 18 years or older living in households with telephones within the coterminous United States.</universe>
                <dataKind>survey data</dataKind>
            </sumDscr>
        </stdyInfo>
        <method>
            <dataColl>                
                <timeMeth>Longitudinal: Trend / Repeated Cross-section</timeMeth>
                <sampProc>National sample of telephone numbers from cell (RDD) sampling frame</sampProc>
                <collMode>computer-assisted telephone interview (CATI)</collMode>
            </dataColl>
            <notes>Information on the Index of Consumer Sentiment, the Index of Current Economic Conditions, and the Index of Consumer Expectations and how they were created can be found in the P.I. Codebook</notes>
            <notes>Additional information on the Surveys of Consumers can be found by visiting the &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.sca.isr.umich.edu/&quot;&gt; Surveys of Consumers Website.&lt;/a&gt;</notes>
        </method>
        <dataAccs>
            <setAvail media="online">
                <accsPlac URI="https://doi.org/10.3886/ICPSR37901.v1">Inter-university Consortium for Political and Social Research</accsPlac>
            </setAvail>
            <useStmt>                
                <restrctn>Available to ICPSR member institutions. This data collection may not be used for any purpose other than statistical reporting and analysis. Use of these data to learn the identity of any person or establishment is prohibited. To protect respondent privacy, some of the data files in this collection are restricted from general dissemination. To obtain these restricted files researchers must agree to the terms and conditions of a Restricted Data Use Agreement. Visit https://doi.org/10.3886/ICPSR37901.v1 to apply for access to restricted data.</restrctn>
                <conditions>ICPSR Terms of Use <ExtLink URI="https://www.icpsr.umich.edu/web/ICPSR/studies/37901/terms"/></conditions>
            </useStmt>
        </dataAccs>
    </stdyDscr>
    <fileDscr>
        <fileTxt>
            <fileName ID="ICPSR-37901-0000">Study-Level Files</fileName>
        </fileTxt>
    </fileDscr>
    <fileDscr>
        <fileTxt>
            <fileName ID="ICPSR-37901-0002">Restricted-Use Data</fileName>
        </fileTxt>
    </fileDscr>
    <fileDscr>
        <fileTxt>
            <fileName ID="ICPSR-37901-0001">Public-Use Data</fileName>
        </fileTxt>
    </fileDscr>
</codeBook>